Gorken Mimioglu, M.S.

0650 SW Gaines St. #2105, Portland, OR 97239 (C) 503.810.8914 (E) gorken.mimioglu@gmail.com

Professional Profile

Broad international experience in engineering, software, and manufacturing companies with strong leadership, marketing and sales, and project management skills. Multi-task-, and detail-oriented with a firm ability to communicate effectively with technology, business, and executive audiences. Personable, resourceful, proactive, and talented with a solid background in engineering and management. Proven success in identifying and bringing in financial investment, creating strategic partnerships, and lead generation and marketing. Certified Green Belt in Six Sigma.

Core Competencies

- · Project Management
- · Lead Generation & Marketing
- Business Development
- New Product Development
- Strategic Planning & Execution
- Direct & Indirect Sales
- · Contract & Price Negotiation
- · Patents, Trademarks

- Start-up & Mid-Size Corporations
- Partnerships
- · Product Pricing Strategy
- Market Research
- Profit & Loss Management
- · Trade Shows, Seminars, Presentations
- · Team building & Mentoring
- · Internal & External Client Relations

Professional Experience

Business and Technology Consultant, Silver A.S., Portland, OR (December 2011 to Current)

- Provide leadership in the US of a mid-size European manufacturer in support of their most vital global initiatives.
- Help manage and deliver tasks that include assessments, solution development and decision making, complex technology implementation, and portfolio management.
- Bring analytical skills, methodologies, and efficient strategic thinking to build stronger organizational capabilities, drive revenue growth, lead transformative change, integrate technology, and reduce overhead costs. Develop presentations, and sales and marketing programs.

Director, Desinnova Technologies, Inc., Portland, OR (October 2009 to December 2011)

- Prepared the business plan and co-found Desinnova in 2009.
- · Raised and successfully brought in financial investment.
- · Had Desinnova admitted to the Portland State University incubator through a vigorous application process.
- · Oversaw daily operations, business development, partner and customer relations, and sales and marketing.
- · Co-managed project "Intuition Control" using Agile Software Project Management with Scrum.
- · Mobile application development in Apple and Android platforms.
- Managed a team of 18 including members from US, Ecuador, India, and Turkey.
- Prepared and submitted 5 full-patent applications and received trademarks.
- · Organized and attended exhibits at major technology trade shows.
- Created strategic technology partnerships with industry leaders such as Sony.
- Prepared and gave presentations to stakeholders, prospective customers, industry leaders, and students of Portland State University.
- Marketing collateral, visual demo, and web design with search engine optimization (SEO)
- · Managed client relations through use of Microsoft Dynamics CRM and Salesforce.com
- Prepared technical/white papers, press releases, and blogs.
- Procurement and contract management, and freelancer coordination.

Engineer and Deputy Project Manager, Kittelson & Associates, Inc. (KAI) Orlando, FL (September 2006 to September 2009)

 Act as deputy project manager on the five-year KAI Orlando-FDOT District 5 Growth Management contract Comprehensive Plan Amendment review task. Also, conduct Development of Regional Impact (DRI)

- reviews for the same contract.
- Manage and deliver tasks of local, regional, national, and international transportation
 engineering/planning projects in areas including growth management and urban planning, research,
 geometric design, traffic impact analysis, safety, and transit.
- · Lead firm- and office-wide marketing initiatives.
- Prepare winning project proposals such as the proposals for Charlotte County and Lee County Metropolitan Planning Organizations' On-going Consulting Services in Florida.
- Act as the Information Technologies (IT) liaison of the KAI Orlando office for the KAI IT Department.
- Represent the firm at national and international events such as receptions, conferences and seminars.

Engineer, Cardno Eppell Olsen (CEO) - Brisbane, Australia (July 2007 to February 2008)

- Became the youngest and first international employee of KAI to be given the opportunity to go on an exchange to work with CEO of Australia.
- Deliver tasks of various civil engineering projects.
- · Work in CEO Brisbane and Gold Coast offices on projects from various cities and regions of Australia.
- · Prepare project proposals.
- · Represent CEO at client events.

Education

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon 2006

MS in Engineering Management

- Graduate Assistant and Office Manager
- Concentration in Project Management and Product Marketing
- Completed Capstone in Technology Foresight and Marketing
- · The Outstanding Student Award, Department of Engineering and Technology Management
- Nominated for Outstanding Graduating Graduate Student Award, College of Engineering and Computer Science
- Portland State University Student Ambassador: Selected on the basis of academic excellence, communication skills, a commitment to problem solving, productive team member, and demonstration of strong leadership skills within the University setting as well as in the community, 2005 - 2006

Baskent University, Ankara, Turkey 2003 BS in Statistics and Computer Science Dean's List, Fall 2002- Spring 2003

, ,

Certifications, Publications, and Affiliations

- · Six Sigma Green Belt
- · Cisco SMB (Small and Medium Business) Engineer
- Cisco SMB Account Manager
- VMware Sales Professional (VSP)
- VMware Technical Sales Professional (VTSP)
- Tugrul U. Daim and Gorken Mimioglu, "Mass transportation: a Portland area case study", *International Journal of Innovation and Sustainable Development 2012 Vol. 6, No.3 pp. 305 323*
- · Omega Rho International Honor Society, Member

Languages

Fluent: English, Turkish

· Conversational: Spanish, Italian

Technical Skills

- · Windows, Mac OS, VMware
- · Apple iWork, MS Project, MS Visio, MS Office
- Adobe Acrobat Pro, Adobe PS4
- MS SharePoint

- · C, Objective-C, Cocoa Touch, XHTML
- SAP, Sugar CRM, salesforce.com
- · AutoCAD, MicroStation, ArcGIS
- · CorelDRAW X5, Dreamweaver